A Guide to the Papers of C. Brian Kelly, 1959-1978
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of C. Brian Kelly 1959-1978
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10566
Ca. 5,000 items (12 boxes); ca. 4.5 linear shelf feet.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The Kelly Papers were a gift to the Library from Mr. C. Brian Kelly, of the Department of English, Wilson Hall, the University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia, on September 28, 1983.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of ca. 5,000 items (12 boxes); ca. 4.5 linear shelf feet), 1959-1978, research files of C. Brian Kelly, a staff writer for the Washington Star. These papers include reporter and teletype copies of news stories, newspaper clippings, pres release, correspondence, photographs, and printed and miscellaneous related items. Kelly was based in Richmond, and reported on Virginia politics and related events including the activities of the General Assembly and the governors, and on political campaigns. Most of the material pertains to state-wide elections for governor, lieutenant governor, attorney general, and the U.S. Senate. Prominent politicians mentioned include William Battle, Harry F. Byrd, Jr., Clive DuVal, Linwood Holton, Henry Howell, Andrew Miller, and John Warner. Other topics addressed by the General Assembly or related to the Virginia political scene include wetlands, kepone, desegregation in Prince Edward County, the Bicentennial, the Potomac River Basin Compact, the 1977 bond issue, VEPCO rates and the North Anna controversy, and inaugural festivities.
Of special interest is a photostatic copy of a letter from Libby Prison, Richmond, November 12, 1863, from Union Colonel Abel D. Streight of the Fifty-first Indiana to Indiana Governor Oliver P. Morton. In his letter Streight complains of conditions in the prison; he and his men had been captured by Confederate General Nathan Bedford Forrest after attempting raids in Georgia and Alabama. Streight and over one hundred Union officers eventually escaped from the prison by a tunnel in 1864. The original letter was a gift to Virginia Governor-elect Linwood Holton.
Arrangement
The collection is divided into two series: General Subject Files, and Political Campaigns and Elections. Folders are arranged alphabetically and chronologically.
Contents List
- Series I: General Subject Files (Box 1-7)
  - Agriculture: Virginia 1968-1969, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Bicentennial 1976 (Box 1)
  - Black Student Union, University of Maryland n.d. (Box 1)
  - Bonds: Virginia 1977 (Box 1)
  - Budget 1975-1977 (Box 1)
  - Consumer Protection [1969?] (Box 1)
  - Correspondence 1960-1978, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Day by Day 1977, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Elections: Stanley, Virginia 1969-1971, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Executive and Legislative Material 1969-1978, n.d., 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Gathright Dam 1971-1974 (Box 1)
  - General Assembly News: Reporter Copy 1969-1977, n.d., 2 folders (Box 2)
  - General Assembly News 1969-1977, n.d., 4 folders (Box 2)
  - Linwood Holton Appointments 1969-1970 (Box 3)
  - Post-Holton Election 1969-1970 (Box 3)
  - Holton Inauguration 1969-1970 (Box 3)
  - Linwood Holton as Governor 1970, 1973, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Kepone 1976-1977 (Box 3)
  - Legislative Issues 1975-1976 (Box 3)
  - Libby Prison (and A.D. Streight) 1970 (Box 3)
  - Life Insurance 1975 (Box 3)
  - Lobbyists 1972-1973, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Mental Health 1968-1969, 1975 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous 1968-1978, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous Subjects: Copy 1973-1977, n.d., 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous Subjects: Reporter Copy 1969, 1973, 1976, n.d. (Box 4)
  - News Clippings 1967-1978, n.d., 2 folders (Box 4)
  - News Releases: Commonwealth of Virginia 1969-1978, n.d. (Box 4)
  - News Releases: Miscellaneous Sources 1973-1978, n.d. (Box 5)
  - News Releases: Miscellaneous Non-Political 1969-1978 (Box 5)
  - News Releases: Miscellaneous Political 1967-1978, n.d., 2 folders (Box 5)
  - News Releases: Paul Trible 1978 (Box 5)
  - News Releases: University of Virginia 1973-1978 (Box 5)
  - Northern Virginia State Legislative Delegation 1966-1967, n.d., Folder 1 of 2 (Box 5)
  - Northern Virginia State Legislative Delegation 1966-1967, n.d., Folder 2 of 2 (Box 6)
  - Political News: Reporter Copy 1969, 1973-1977, n.d. (Box 6)
  - Political News: Copy 1972-1978, 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Potomac River Basin Compact 1967-1970 (Box 6)
  - P.O.W.'s (Virginia) 1969-1970, n.d. (Box 6)
  - Prince Edward County School Case 1959-1961 (Box 7)
  - Solid Wastes Study 1973 (Box 7)
  - Student Protests 1970 (Box 7)
  - VEPCO 1969-1978 (Box 7)
  - Gilbert C. Walker 1969 (Box 7)
- Series II: Political Campaigns & Elections (Box 7-12)
  - Democratic Gubernatorial Primary Campaign News 1969, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Henry Howell: Gubernatorial Primary Campaign Releases 1969 (Box 7)
  - Pollard-Thompson-Farley Primary Campaign Releases 1969 (Box 7)
  - A.P. Miller-Farley Primary Campaign News 1969 (Box 8)
  - William C. Battle: Gubernatorial Primary Campaign Releases 1969 (Box 8)
  - Primary Campaigns 1969 (Box 8)
  - Battle-Reynolds-Miller Election Campaign 1969 (Box 8)
  - Biographies of Candidates 1969 (Box 8)
  - Elections/Campaigns 1969, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Political Campaigns 1969 (Box 9)
  - Holton-Obenshain-Dawbarn-Callaghan Campaign Releases 1969 (Box 9)
  - Harry F. Byrd, Jr.: Candidate for U.S. Senator 1969-1970 (Box 9)
  - DuVal-Rawlings: U.S. Senate Campaign 1970 (Box 9)
  - Haggerty-Branstetter: U.S. Senate Campaign 1970 (Box 9)
  - Primary Election Campaigns 1970 (Box 9)
  - Political News 1972-1975 (Box 9)
  - Political Campaigns and Election Results 1976, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Byrd, Perper, Zumwal: U.S. Senate Campaign 1975-1978 (Box 10)
  - Howell: Democratic Candidate for Nomination for Governor 1976-1977 (Box 10)
  - "Howell for Governor" 1977 (Box 10)
  - Howell: Democratic Candidate for Governor 1977, n.d., 2 folders (Box 10)
  - A.P. Miller: Democratic Candidate for Nomination for Governor 1977 (Box 11)
  - Democratic Candidates for Nomination for Lieutenant Governor and Attorney General 1977 (Box 11)
  - Robb and Lane: Democratic Candidates for Lieutenant Governor and Attorney General 1977 (Box 11)
  - Dalton: Republican Candidate for Nomination for Governor 1977, n.d. (Box 11)
  - Dalton: Republican Candidate for Governor 1977, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Coleman: Republican Candidate for Attorney General 1977-1978 (Box 11)
  - Republican Candidates for Nomination for Lieutenant Governor 1977 (Box 12)
  - Durrette: Republican Candidate for Attorney General 1977 (Box 12)
  - Independent Candidates for Governor 1977 (Box 12)
  - Candidates for Republican Nomination for U.S. Senate 1978 (Box 12)
  - John Warner: Republican Candidate for U.S. Senate 1978, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Candidates for Democratic Nomination for U.S. Senate 1978 (Box 12)
  - A.P. Miller: Democratic Candidate for U.S. Senate 1978 (Box 12)
  - Fickett: Democratic Candidate for Nomination for Seventh Congressional District 1978 (Box 12)